#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nabeelvandayar (LinkedIn) nabeelvandayar.com (Personal)

## Top Skills

Data Engineering Machine Learning Data Analysis

## Languages

English (Full Professional)
Chinese (Mandarin) (Elementary)

### Certifications

Sequence Models

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Convolutional Neural Networks

Data Engineering Nanodegree

Cloud Native Development with

Node.js, Docker, and Kubernetes

#### Honors-Awards

University Entrance Scholarship
Dean's Merit List: Bachelor of
Medicine and Bachelor of Surgery
Year 1

Electronics Merit Award Software Development Merit Award Dean's List

# Nabeel Vandayar

Data and machine learning engineer | Biomedical and electrical engineer | Biomechatronic robotics enthusiast

Johannesburg Area, South Africa

# Summary

I design, implement and manage data pipelines for real-time and scheduled bulk data processing using Python, AWS Redshift and EMR, Azure Databricks and CosmosDB, Apache Airflow, Spark and Kafka, using relational and NoSQL distributed databases. I also build and deploy machine learning models as scalable web services using Tensorflow, Docker, Kubernetes. My research "Hand gesture recognition on low cost hardware" has been published by the IEEE and the Pattern Recognition Association of South Africa. I have degrees in biomedical and electrical engineering and enjoy designing and building electromechanical systems using AI, robotics and the web.

# Experience

Altron

Data Engineer November 2018 - Present (1 year 5 months) South Africa

Data pipeline design | Data modeling | User analytics | Software development | Machine learning solutions | Algorithm development | Big data processing | Real time solutions

MediSwitch, a Division of Altron TMT (Pty) Ltd Data Scientist January 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 7 months) South Africa

Diabetes diagnosis prediction using neural networks | Customer data visualization | Medical data processing | Principal component analysis

## Education

University of the Witwatersrand

Master of Science (MSc) in Engineering, Biomedical Engineering · (2019 - 2020)

University of the Witwatersrand
Bachelor of Science (BSc) in Engineering , Electrical and
Information · (2017 - 2018)

University of the Witwatersrand
Bachelor of Engineering Science (BEng), Biomedical
Engineering · (2014 - 2017)

University of the Witwatersrand
Bachelor of Medicine, Bachelor of Surgery - MBBCh
(Deferred), Medicine · (2013 - 2013)

Jeppe High School for Boys Matric · (2008 - 2012)